

PORTFOLIO GITHUB

LINKEDIN

Canada

+1(438) 341 5520

manzotsingh@gmail.com

# **Professional Summary**

Video Game Developer with experience in Game Engines, object-oriented programming, and writing clean code. Accomplished in elevating games with new and improved strategies. Ability to quickly learn and use new programming languages, tools, and software applications.

# Skills

- Experience with Game Engines (Unity, Unreal and Gamemaker)
- High Proficiency in programming languages
  (C# and C++)
- Experience With Web Programming (HTML, CSS, Javascript)
- Experience with source control and project management tools (Git, Github and Jira)

- Understanding of Database Management Systems(SQL / RDBMS).
- Game balancing and optimization.
- Troubleshooting and problem-solving.
- Organizational & Time Management Skills.
- Strong team, communicative, interpersonal skills and self-motivated.

# Work Experience

### **Unity Game Developer**

January 2021- July 2021

Metavision Labs – Toronto, Ontario

- Worked with team to shape game features and optimize gameplay at scale.
- Produce high-quality, clean code for client projects.
- Created innovative designs with the use of programming languages and tools.

# **Unity Game Developer (Intern)**

May 2020 - December 2020

Dragon Slumber - Montreal, Quebec

- Developed game systems, individual gameplay features, and player progressions.
- Analyzed live data and player feedback to continually optimize existing game experience.
- Collaborated with team to create and implement innovative UI design.

#### **Software Developer Intern**

April 2018 to July 2018

New Generation Technologies Ltd. – Chandigarh, Punjab, India

- Learned software engineering process improvements and best practices.
- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre-released software project development.
- Maintained and upgraded products to deliver smooth-running systems.

# Education

Attestation of College Studies: Video Games Programming Jan

January 2019 - January 2021

Institut Supérieur D'Informatique - Montreal, QC

Coursework: Game Engines, Object-Oriented Programming, Games Mathematics, Graphics

Libraries, 2D/3D Tools, Web Programming, Artificial Intelligence

Bachelor's of Technology: Computer Science

May 2014 – July 2018

Doaba Institute Of Engineering And Technology - Kharar, Punjab, India

Coursework: Algorithms and Data Structure, Object-Oriented Programming, Operating Systems,

Computer Graphics, Artificial Intelligence

# **Projects**

# 3D RPG Game (Unity3D, C#, Action RPG) (Github)

Currently in Development, a 3D Game using Unity URP, C#, inbuilt and custom made Unity tools. Featuring Dynamic UI, Interactable NPC's, Zelda game like Inventory System, Quest Manager with both main and side quests, Melee, ranged and blocking combat with player stamina system.

### Grapplu - The Beginning (Unity 2D, C#, Action Platformer) (Play Here)

2D Platfomer game made in Unity with features like Melee Combat, Grapple Hook, Time slow, Time Rewind, 3 types of enemies including ranged and melee, 2 Bosses with unique abilities, 2 fully playable levels.

### Doodle Jump Clone (Gamemaker Studio, GML, Arcade) (Play Here)

A Strategy based multi-Level 2D puzzle Game, with a dark and Challenging Environment. 2D Dynamic Lights and Shaders used in real time environment.

### Movolit (Unity 2D, C#, Puzzle Platformer) (Github)

A Strategy based multi-Level 2D puzzle Game, with a dark and Challenging Environment. 2D Dynamic Lights and Shaders used in real time environment.

# The Unrepairable Tower (Unity 3D, C#, Casual Game) (Github)

My first game jam game with a team of 8 people that we made in 2 days. In this game you have to reapir the tower which has some problems on each level. Its a endless tower where you rush to fix floor before its too late.

# Spineless: A Blank Tale (Unity3D, C#, Action VR Game) (Github)

Virtual Reality Game made in Unity3d, where you are on a wheelchair and you shoot through enemies and kill the boss to win. It features a indoor level, ranged and melee enemies, one boss with 3 skills, stun gun, sword and pick able items and power ups.